Contactar

+573173780011 (Home) fabiancpl91@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fabiancpl (LinkedIn) fabiancpl github io/ (Parsanal)

fabiancpl.github.io/ (Personal)

Aptitudes principales

Data Science

Machine Learning

Software Development

Languages

Spanish (Native or Bilingual) English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure

Modernizing Data Lakes and Data Warehouses with GCP

Honors-Awards

IEEE Latin America and the Caribbean Discretional Director's Award

IEEE Computer Society Richard E. Merwin Scholarship

Fabian Camilo Peña

Lead Data Scientist at Analytic Lab Colombia

Extracto

I have a master degree in Information Engineering with focus on visual analytics and machine learning. I have implemented data analytics and big data solutions in contexts such as smart cities, transportation, environmental management, tax administration and public health. In addition, I have experience in software development and cloud computing.

Experiencia

Analytic Lab Lead Data Scientist febrero de 2019 - Present (1 año 4 meses)

Design and development of a smart cities platform for transportation and environmental management. Lead a team composed by data scientists and software developers building machine learning models, data visualizations and microservices based on multiple open-source technologies running on Google Cloud Platform.

EUD - Fundación de Egresados de la Universidad Distrital Course Instructor

diciembre de 2017 - Present (2 años 6 meses)

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Teaching activities for the big data and data analytics course. Development of theoretical and practical sessions with a duration of 80 hours.

Universidad de Los Andes Research Assistant enero de 2017 - diciembre de 2018 (2 años)

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Design and development of solutions based on data analytics and big data for the CAOBA Alliance and its partners, principally government companies. Implementation of machine learning models, data transformation and visualization software using open-source technologies.

Green Tech

Software Development Consultant abril de 2016 - junio de 2017 (1 año 3 meses)

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Software development and support for electronic payment systems. Design and development of frontend on AngularJs and REST webservices.

Of Business

Project Lead

noviembre de 2014 - abril de 2016 (1 año 6 meses)

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Management and implementation of projects of virtualization and information security. Administration of VMware, diagnostic of application and database servers and implementation of domain controller and terminal server hostings.

IBM

Intern

julio de 2014 - noviembre de 2014 (5 meses)

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Software development for the National Savings Fund (Fondo Nacional de Ahorro) based on Java Enterprise Edition, REST webservices and Javascript. I was also involved in the development of store procedures in DB2.

One-Click S.A.S

Software Developer

junio de 2012 - octubre de 2013 (1 año 5 meses)

Bogotá D.C. Area, Colombia

Requirement analysis and software development based on Java Enterprise Edition, Vaadin, Oracle and IBM WebSphere Application Server.

Educación

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Probability and Basic Inference · (2020 - 2020)

Universidad de Los Andes

Master's degree, Information Engineering · (2017 - 2019)

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas

Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering (2008 - 2015)